执行了六个月的任务
You know, after six months,
火星越看越像考艾岛了
Mars is starting to remind me of Kauai,
只不过没有水
Except without the water
也没有穿泳衣的美女  也没有空气
or the hot girls in bikinis or the air.
我真想看看美女啊
What I wouldn't give for a hot girl.
都这么久了  看个丑女也行
Hell, after all this time, I'd even take an ugly one,
如果她装在纸袋里
Assuming she came with a paper bag.
真会说话  里奇伍德
Oh, real classy, Richwood.
赶紧修好短路
Just repair the short,
确保4B线圈没有烧坏
and make sure the four-b coil isn't fried.
电力网不能坏掉
We can't afford to have the power grid compromised.
是  舰长
Aye-aye, captain.
糟糕
Oh, boy.
坏消息  烧坏了
Bad news. It's charred.
我可能得换掉动力耦合器了
I may have to replace the power coupling
并重启A级系统
and reboot A-level systems...
没收到  里奇伍德  有干扰
Didn't read that, Richwood. Interference.
重复
Come again.
小心
Watch out!
汤姆
Tom?
Tom!
好诶
Yes!
我等不及脱下我的...
I can't wait to take off my...
鞋了
...shoes.
爸爸  贝克特
Dad. Beckett.
看来别想安静在家度过一晚了
So much for a quiet evening at home.
我以为你们今晚要工作到很晚
I thought you guys were working late tonight.
今天没什么案子  我们早下班了
Slow murder day. We got off early.
你在玩激光枪战
You're playing laser tag?
不带我
Without me?
那是我的装备吗
Is that my gear?
爸爸  贝克特  这是大卫
Oh, dad, Beckett, this is David.
他跟我打赌说我打不过他
He bet me I couldn't beat him.
-她把你海扁了  是吧  -是啊
- She trounced you, didn't she? - Yeah.
天呐
Oh, my,
这下面是怎么回事
What is going on down here?
显然发生的事太多了  那是我的睡衣吗
Far too much, apparently. Uh, are those my pajamas?
真抱歉  本
I'm so sorry, Ben.
我的家人  这是本杰明
Um, family, Benjamin.
本  这是我的家人
Ben, meet my family.
卡塞尔  有杀人案
Castle, we got a murder.
要破  不是要犯下
Uh, to solve, not to commit.
再见
Bye.
那是我最软的一件睡衣了
But those were my softest pajamas,
现在我只能烧掉了
and now I'm gonna have to burn them.
只有我觉得
Is it just me, or is the loft
家里现在越来越挤了吗
getting awfully small these days?
四个大人住在一起
Well, four adults together in one space...
我们肯定要妨碍到彼此
We're bound to step on each other's toes.
今晚的人格外多
Yeah, well, there's a lot more toes than usual tonight.
伙计们  你们能来太好了
Hey, guys. Glad you're here.
你们肯定想看看的  尤其你  卡塞尔
You're gonna want to see this, especially you, Castle.
这是什么地方啊
What is this place?
是任务控制中心
It's mission control.
那是火星
And that's Mars.
那是尸体
And there's your body.
被害人在火星
Our victim is on Mars?
秘密火星任务的谣言是真的
The "Secret manned mission to Mars" rumors were true.
我就知道
I knew it!
这是不是超出我们的管辖范围了
You know, this might be a little out of our jurisdiction.
那不是火星
It's not Mars.
这位是行动指挥艾德·莱德利
This is operations director Ed Redley.
-这是贝克特和莱恩警探  -卡塞尔
- This is detectives Beckett and Ryan. - Castle.
你们所看到的是
Uh, what you're seeing is a live feed
真正火星任务之前的
from a simulation we're conducting
模拟任务直播信号
in advance of a real Mars mission.
你们是哪方面  宇航局吗
Who's "We"? NASA?
这是火星2018任务  由个人资助
It's the Mars 2018 project. We're privately funded.
没错  韦格·詹森  那个网络亿万富翁
Yes, by Viggo Jansen, the internet billionaire.
他许诺2018年要送人上火星
He promised to put humans on Mars by 2018.
还办了比赛
Held a competition and everything.
我报名加入项目  但没进去
I signed up for the program, but I didn't get in.
你报名去火星
Wait, you signed up to go to Mars?
-什么时候  -几年前
- When? - A couple years ago.
我当时在哪
Where was I?
我们当时在吵架
We were fighting.
被害人  驾驶员汤姆·里奇伍德被该是
The victim, pilot Tom Richwood, was supposedly alone
独自一人在火星表面进行维修任务
on the, uh, planet's surface conducting repairs.
我们当时遭遇了通讯中断
We were in a communication blackout,
这是模拟状态的一部分
part of simulating planetary conditions,
这时任务指挥官打破规程
when the mission commander broke protocol
跟我们说汤姆死了
to tell us they found Tom dead.
他们认为并非意外
They don't think it was an accident.
我想看看尸体  模拟地在哪
Well, I'd like to see the body. So where is the simulation?
在楼下
A couple of floors below us,
这说来容易做起来难
and that's easier said than done.
为了模拟火星环境
In order to mimic conditions on Mars
也避免作弊
as well as discourage any cheating,
模拟室里满是毒气
the simulation is filled with noxious gas.
不会致死
Right, it won't kill you,
但会引起严重不适和红疹
but it will induce severe nausea and a rash.
要好几天才能排净模拟室的空气
It would take several days to vent the sim
让里面气体可呼吸  所以你们如果想进去
to make the air breathable, so if you want to go in,
就得穿太空服
you're gonna need to wear space suits.
最棒的案子
Best case ever!
这边吗
This way?
能跟我们讲讲被害人吗
What can you tell us about the victim?
汤姆·里奇伍德是任务的驾驶员
Well, Tom Richwood was the mission pilot.
前海军飞行员  在宇航局上过天
Former navy top gun, did a tour with NASA.
家人呢
What about family?
没有  所以他是任务首选人物
None, which made him the perfect candidate for the mission.
他击败了世界上一些
He beat out some of the smartest,
最聪明  最有竞争力的候选人
most competitive candidates in the world
加入了这项首个人类上火星的任务
to be a part of the first manned team to Mars.
-他们都是这样  -里面还有谁
- They all did. - Who else is inside?
剩余四位宇航员
Our four remaining astronauts.
团队医疗专家哈伦博士在等你
The team's medical specialist, Dr. Haroun, is waiting for you.
最近有人进出过模拟室吗
So, has anyone been in or out of the simulation recently?
不  这是一项全密封9个月的实验
No. It's a sealed nine-month experiment.
宇航员六个月前
No one's been in or out
进入后就没有人进出过
since the astronauts entered six months ago.
-那么凶手可能就在他们之中  -嗯
- Which means one of them probably did it. - Yeah.
只有三套宇航服
There's only three suits.
没事  我们不用都进去
Um, that's okay. We don't all need to go in.
-我回大堂去录口供  -不是吧
- I'll go take statements back at the facility. - Seriously?
你不想上火星吗
You don't want to go to Mars?
其一  那不是火星
"A," It's actually not Mars,
其二  我在地球就很开心
and "B," I'm happy here on earth,
你好好玩吧  卡塞尔
but have fun, Castle.
我一定会的
Trust me, I will.
闹完了吗
Are you done?
没有
No.
终于来到了火星
Finally made it to Mars.
我都不用进行宇航员训练
I didn't even have to go to astronaut training.
你真报名去火星了啊
So, you really signed up to go to Mars, huh?
那多酷啊
Wouldn't that be cool?
对你不算  但对我多酷啊
I mean, not so much for you, but for me.
警探
Detectives?
我是拉什曼·哈伦博士  生物科学官
I'm Dr. Rusham Haroun, the bioscience officer
他在那边
He's over here.
没人看到事情经过吗
And nobody saw this happen?
没有  我们都在模拟舱内
No, we were all in the module.
我们听到了他尖叫
We heard him scream.
他一定是摔在了耦合器线圈上
He must have fallen into the coupling coil,
因为那时电力中断了
because right then the power went out.
等我和安琪拉出来的时候  他已经死了
By the time Angela and I got out here, he was gone.
我们又花了10分钟才恢复了电力
It took us another 10 minutes to get the power restored.
看似是刀伤
It looks like a stab wound.
而且用力很猛
Delivered with a lot of force.
那凶器呢
Well, where's the murder weapon?
没有
There wasn't one.
但他的一件工具  他的螺丝刀不见了
But one of his tools, his screwdriver, is missing.
这个样子的
It looks like this.
这里石头很多  没有脚印
It's pretty rocky around here. No footprints.
而且凶手大概穿着宇航服
And, since the killer was probably wearing a suit,
也不会留下DNA
there's not gonna be any DNA.
把尸体送去停尸间查查看吧
Let's get his body to the morgue and find out.
让鉴证组过来  把这里好好搜索一下
And get CSU down here. I want this place searched.
如果没人进出过
If no one's been in or out,
那么凶器就还在这里
Then that murder weapon is still inside here.
哈伦博士  我想跟其他宇航员谈谈
Dr. Haroun, I'd like to speak to the other astronauts, please.
他们在里面  跟我来
They're inside. Follow me.
人类的一宗小小谋杀案
One small murder for man,
人类的一个大谜题
one giant mystery for mankind.
就算你低声说  大家也都能听到
Even when you whisper, everyone can hear you.
我可能得换掉动力耦合器了  并重启
I may need to replace the power coupling and reboot...
没收到  里奇伍德  有干扰
Didn't read that, Richwood. Interference.
重复
Come again.
小心
Watch out!
其他你们都知道了
You know the rest.
这事发生时你们都在哪
And where were each one of you when this happened?
安琪拉  拉什曼和我都在指挥模拟器里
Angela, Rusham, and I were here, in the command module.
米哈伊尔在工程区
Mikhail was over in engineering.
从工程区能进入外部吗
And is there access to the outside from engineering?
有一个紧急舱门
There is emergency hatch,
但如果我穿过舱门  警报会触响的
but if I had gone through it, the alarm would have sounded.
而且作为项目的一部分  我们都受到严密监视
Plus, as part of the program, we're all closely monitored.
以防我们丧失意识
In case we lose consciousness
或者宇航员出舱的时候宇航服发生故障
or there's a suit malfunction on an E.V.A.,
我们皮肤里都有追踪器
we all have trackers under our skin.
米拉会记录我们所有人的行动
And M.I.R.A. keeps a record of all our movements.
米拉是谁
Who's M.I.R.A.?
任务电脑
That's what we call the mission computer.
我想看看这些记录
Well, I'd like to take a look at those records.
我乐意为您提供您需要的一切记录
I will be happy to provide you with any records you require,
贝克特探长
Detective Beckett.
-她会说话  -嗯
- It talks? - Yeah.
我们把她视为任务的第六位成员
We think of her as the sixth member of the crew.
这是不是有点《2001太空漫游》
Isn't that a little "2001"?
她的程序是学习适应型的
She is programmed to learn and adapt,
但比起哈尔[电影里的机器人]  她更像siri
but she's more siri than H.A.L.
问她你在哪
Ask her where you are.
米拉  我们在哪
M.I.R.A., where are we?
你在火星北部低地的
You are aboard the vessel Tensing Norgay
丹增·诺盖号
in the northern lowlands of Mars.
她真以为自己在火星
She actually thinks she's on Mars.
不论如何  我得请你们
Regardless, I'm gonna need to ask all of you
跟我去一趟分局  我好妥当进行审问
to join me at the precinct so I can interview you properly.
这是个问题
That...could be a problem.
抱歉  探长
I'm sorry, detective.
我不能让你带走宇航员
I can't let you remove the astronauts.
我没这个权力
I don't have that kind of authority.
那谁有
Well, then, who does?
我
That would be me.
我的宇航员哪里也不会去
And my astronauts aren't going anywhere.
那是韦格·詹森啊
That's Viggo Jansen. The Viggo Jansen.
探长  如果我们现在停工
Detective, if we shut down now,
我们会失去数月的宝贵数据
we will lose months of priceless data.
数百万的实验就此白费
Millions of dollars' worth of experiments will be compromised.
我们会损失半年  我们没那个时间了
We'll lose half a year, and we don't have that time.
詹森先生  这不是请求
Mr. Jansen, it's not a request.
有人被杀了
A man has been murdered.
我需要进行调查
I need to conduct an investigation.
我会尽全力协助你的
And I will do everything in my power to help you...
但不能关闭我的模拟室
Short of shutting down my sim.
火星是我们这一代的太空竞赛
Mars is our generation's space race,
我的团队会是第一支上火星的团队
And my team's gonna be first...
不是中国人  或火星一号
Not the chinese or Mars one
或是那个自我膨胀的电影制片人  伊恩·拉什尔爵士
or that puffed-up movie producer, sir Ian Rasher.
我可以申请法院命令强迫你
I can get a court order to compel you.
凭我的法律团队  你要花上几个月了
And with my legal team, it'll take you months.
或者  我们可以合作
Or we can work together.
我给你所有你需要的权限
I give you all the access you need,
让我的模拟室继续运行
and my simulation keeps running.
好吧  现在可以
Fine. For now.
但如果被我发现那几个人中有人是凶手
But if I find out any of those people are responsible,
你休想阻止我带走他们
you won't stop me from removing them.
那个  根据这份追踪数据
Yeah. Well, according to this tracking data,
他们似乎都不是凶手
none of them seem responsible.
汤姆估计死亡时间时
They were all exactly where they said they were
他们都在自己所说的位置
at Tom's approximate time of death.
甚至确认了任务探测车
It even confirms that the mission's rover
在凶案发生时仍停在太空栖息地
was still parked at the habitat at the time of the incident.
看来我的"机器反攻"理论行不通了
Well, there goes my "Rise of the machines" theory.
如果里面的人都查实了
Okay, so if all the people inside are accounted for,
那凶手一定来自模拟室外
then our killer must have come from outside of the simulation.
那我们会知道的
We would know.
气闸门是唯一的入口
The airlock door is the only way in or out.
有警报  有监控
It's alarmed and monitored.
打扰  贝克特探长
Uh, excuse me. Detective Beckett,
栖息地内有发给你的讯息
there's a message coming in for you from the habitat.
如果可以  我放在屏幕上
I can put it on the monitor if you like.
好的
Yeah, please.
埃斯波  有什么发现
Hey, Espo, what do you got?
我正在检查被害人的视频日志
I was just going through our victim's video diaries.
你得看看这个
There's something you need to see.
六个月了
Six months in,
我知道心理实验也是任务的一部分
and I know part of this mission is a psych experiment.
或许封闭的环境开始影响到我了
Maybe the close quarters are starting to get to me,
但我好像开始看到幻象
but I think I'm starting to see things.
我今天在外面时  我发誓我看到了人
When I was out there today, I could've sworn I saw someone,
而且这不是第一次了
and it's not the first time.
我知道这不可能  但我觉得这里并不只有我们
I know it's not possible, but I don't think we're alone.
别走动  我可能还有问题
Hang tight. I may have more questions.
讲吧  埃斯波
Go ahead, Espo.
我刚刚跟其他几位宇航员谈过
Hey. So, I just finished talking to the other astronauts.
他们似乎都不知道汤姆在说什么
None of them seem to have any idea what Tom was talking about.
好了  谢谢  埃斯波
All right. Thanks, Espo.
鉴证组刚刚完成了初步检查
CSU just finished their initial sweep.
模拟室里没有别人
There's no one else in that simulation.
汤姆可能真是看到幻象了
It's possible Tom was seeing things.
我们的所有测试均显示
All our tests show that being locked
与他人一起关在封闭空间里会对人的心理造成影响
in a confined space with others can play tricks on your mind.
但幻觉不会杀人
Only, delusions don't kill.
而且  如果汤姆所言属实
And, if what Tom said was true,
那么杀他的人
then whoever killed him
或许能不被察觉地进出模拟室
might have been able to get in and out undetected.
我说了  探长
I told you, detective,
凭我们的安保力度  这不可能
given our security, that's impossible.
先生
Sir.
或许没那么绝对
Maybe not.
按莱恩警探的要求
At detective Ryan's request,
我检查了我们所有的安全系统
I ran a check on all our security systems.
一切看起来很正常  直到我开始检查深层代码
Everything looked normal until I got into the deep code.
看到吗
See that?
-天呐  -是什么
- Oh, god. - What is it?
我们的安全系统被入侵了
Our security system's been hacked...
钥匙卡  警报代码
Key cards, alarm codes.
所以有人可能闯入了模拟室
Meaning someone could've broken into the simulation.
从我们的备份文件来看
Based on our back-up files,
这些改动是两天前做的
these changes were made two days ago,
在晚11点10分到11点14之间
sometime between 11:10 and 11:14 at night.
数码追踪显示我们是从外部被入侵的
Digital tracing indicates we were breached from the outside.
有人闯入了我们的防火墙
Someone broke through our firewall.
能查到是谁吗
Can you tell who?
与主机项链的IP地址我们都有登记
We log every I.P. Address that connects to the mainframe.
我正在查那个时间段
I'm running a trace now for that time window.
那个  第三个  这个是陌生IP
There. Third one down. I don't recognize that one.
好  我们应该能查到
All right, we should be able to trace it.
不用  我查了
Don't bother. I just did.
来自民宅无线网络  登记在...
It's coming from a residential wi-fi registered to a...
开玩笑吧
You got to be kidding me.
是谁
Who is it?
克林特·格兰杰  急性子驾驶员
Clint Granger, hothead pilot.
他是申请人之一
He was one of our applicants
但被踢出了项目
until he was kicked out of the program.
为什么被踢走了
Why'd he get kicked out?
他指责汤姆在候选人测试期间给他搞了破坏
He accused Tom of sabotaging him during candidate testing
说这害他错失驾驶员一职
and claimed it cost him the pilot spot.
于是他试图在停车场轧死汤姆
So he tried to run Tom over in the parking lot.
什么时候的事
And when was this?
七个月前
Seven months ago.
不过他确实说过要回来干完这事
But he did say he'd be back to finish the job.
是的  我当时很生气
Yeah, I was pissed.
我现在还是很生气
I'm still pissed.
在最后一轮前他往我的饮料里放了东西
He slipped something into my drink before the final round.
让我反应变慢了
Slowed my reaction time.
所以你就用你的车去撞他
So you tried to run him over with your car?
应该是我去执行那个任务  不是他
It should have been me on that mission, not him.
应该是我留名青史
He stole my spot in history.
要是我说的话  他这是活该倒霉
And you ask me, he got what he deserved.
但我没有杀他
But I did not kill him.
可是我们追踪到网络攻击的源头是你家
And yet we traced that cyber attack to your apartment.
我是个驾驶员  不是电脑极客
I am a pilot, not a computer geek.
即便是任务急需我也写不出那代码
I couldn't rewrite that code if the mission depended on it.
你可能是雇了别人
You could've hired someone.
有可能  但我没有
Yeah, but I didn't.
汤姆被杀的时候
Look, when Tom was getting himself murdered,
我在康乃迪克州跟朋友吃饭
I was at dinner with a friend in Connecticut.
而且有人用我的无线网络进行攻击时
And when that hack took place from my Wi-Fi,
我甚至都不在国内
I wasn't even in the country.
有人在陷害我
Someone's setting me up!
格兰杰的不在场证据被证实了
Granger's alibi checks out.
汤姆·里奇伍德被杀时他的确在跟朋友吃饭
He was at dinner with a friend when Tom Richwood was killed.
黑客攻击那晚呢
What about the night the hack took place?
格兰杰去新斯科舍省[加拿大]看他兄弟了
Granger was visiting his brother in Nova Scotia.
不是他干的
It wasn't him.
火星  新斯科舍省
Mars, Nova Scotia --
这家伙还真是喜欢荒凉的地方
this guy really loves barren landscapes.
拜托  莱恩
Come on, Ryan,
难道你就不想去火星吗
You're telling me you have no desire to go to Mars?
我还是喜欢不用氧气筒呼吸
I prefer my oxygen without a can.
你的冒险精神哪去了
Where's your sense of adventure?
还有探索精神
Of exploration?
使命感
Of... destiny?
如果让我飞几千英里去看一个没有生命的[星]球
If I want to fly thousands of miles to see a lifeless orb,
我还不如去珍妮的祖母家
I can just visit Jenny's grandmother.
都有敌对的气氛  都有寒冷的温度
Same hostile environment, same freezing temperatures,
都有有害的气体
Same noxious atmosphere.
什么情况
Huh? "Huh," What?
有段视频  是在黑客攻击那晚
Well, this is a video of Granger's apartment lobby
格兰杰公寓大厅的  来看看
the night of the hack -- check it out.
这家伙晚上11:05进入的大楼
This guy enters the building at 11:05 P.M.,
就在黑客攻击之前
Just before the hack took place.
再看看这个
Now watch.
15分钟之后
15 minutes later.
他离开了大楼
He leaves the building.
他可能是盗用了格兰杰的无线网络
He could've piggybacked on Granger's wireless
对模拟室的安全网络实施了攻击
and used that to carry out the attack on the simulation security.
是的  可他是谁呢
Yeah, but who is he?
名字叫乔治·雷尔
Name's George Reyes.
火星2018的人立刻认出了他
The folks down at Mars 2018 recognized him immediately.
他是高级设备工程师
He's the senior facilities engineer,
昨天请了病假
And he called in sick yesterday.
之后就没人再联系上他了
Nobody's been able to reach him since.
他有没有动机
Did he have a motive to break
潜入模拟室  杀掉汤姆呢
into the simulation and kill Tom?
没人知道  不过他的同事们说
Not that anyone knew, but his colleagues say
他最近几天一直行为很神秘
that he's been acting secretive the last couple of days,
自从接到了他妻子的信件后就这样
ever since receiving a private communique from his wife.
他妻子跟这有什么关系
What does his wife got to do with this?
有很大关系  知道他妻子是谁吗
Maybe everything. Ask me who his wife is.
是谁
Who's his wife?
安琪拉·奥维拉  是其中一个航天员
Angela Olvera, one of the other astronauts.
那信的内容是什么
So, what was on the message?
我是想让乔治知道我想离婚了
I was letting George know that I wanted out of our marriage.
他在太空跟他分手
You broke up with him from space?
他一直在给我发情书
He was sending me all these sweet e-mails.
我不能让这继续下去了
I couldn't let it go on.
我必须得告诉他我爱上别人了
I had to tell him that I'd fallen for someone else,
我们任务里的人
someone on the mission.
是汤姆吗
Was it Tom?
不  不是汤姆
No. Not Tom.
天哪
Oh, God.
怎么了
What?
安琪拉
Angela?
我在信里没说是谁
I didn't say who it was in my letter.
可能他以为是汤姆
Maybe he thought it was Tom.
他有理由这么认为吗
Did he have reason to?
是的
Yeah, he did.
汤姆在训练期间一直在追求我
Tom wouldn't stop hitting on me all through training.
乔治跟他说如果他不住手  就要付出代价的
George told him if he didn't stop, he'd make him pay.
找到他了  在机场
We found him. He's at the airport.
刚买了一张去旧金山的机票
Just bought a ticket to San Francisco.
机场的保安逮住了他
Airport security just picked him up.
安琪拉和我是一个团队
We were a team, Angela and me.
我们要么一起去火星  要么都不去
We were gonna go to Mars together or not at all.
可当她入选  而我落选时
But when she got in and I didn't,
我也不能妨碍她的事业
I couldn't stand in her way.
看着她离开地球已经够让你难受的了
Hard enough to have her leave the planet,
可看到她为了别人离开你...
but to leave you for someone else...
你一定很绝望
you must have been devastated.
是非常绝望
Try utterly destroyed.
所以你才黑进了安保系统吗
Is that why you hacked security?
为了破坏模拟室
In order to break into the simulation
并杀死你以为是安琪拉情人的人
and kill the man that you thought was Angela's lover?
我说了  我跟汤姆的死没有关系
I'm telling you, I had nothing to do with Tom's death.
我是想破坏这次任务
I was going to sabotage the mission.
我想如果模拟室出现重大故障
I figured if the simulation suffered a catastrophic failure,
就能够拖延这个项目
it would set the program back,
安琪拉就能回到我身边
and Angela would come home to me.
但是我临阵退缩了
But I chickened out.
那次攻击
The hack,
嫁祸到格兰杰身上
setting it up to lead back to Granger --
我只敢做到那一步了
that's as far as I got.
我没进去过
I never went inside,
也没杀过任何人
and I sure as hell didn't kill anyone.
那你为什么要离开这里
Then why were you leaving town?
她甩了我
She dumped me.
我怎么还能继续在那里工作
How was I supposed to keep going to work there?
我需要一个新的开始
I needed a fresh start.
自从我收到她的信后
And since I got her letter,
我好几个晚上都在奥马里酒吧借酒消愁
I've spent nights drowning my sorrows at O'malley's.
汤姆被杀时我就在那里
That's where I was when Tom was murdered.
-你可以去问他们  -好吧  本
- You can ask them. - Okay, Ben.
还有谁能利用你的攻击
So who else could've used your hack
穿过模拟室的气闸门
to get through the simulation's airlock?
需要用我的生物特征才行  没人做得到
It was calibrated to my biometrics. No one else could've used it.
-但的确有人做到了  -不
- But someone did. - No.
就算有人进去了  也是通过别的方法
If they got in, they did it some other way.
没有别的方法了
There is no other way.
这我可不确定
I'm not so sure about that.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
我研究过设施的规划设计
I studied the facility plans.
模拟室就像一座银行金库
The simulation is like a bank vault.
想要进去  你得绕过保安
To get in, you got to get past guards,
安保系统  摄像头
security systems, cameras.
不过就像金库一样
But like a bank vault,
只要你有足够的动力
if you're motivated enough,
一定有办法进去
there's always another way in.
你真的认为有人
You really think someone
会通过地道进入模拟室
could've tunneled their way into the sim?
不  但既然乔治的不在场证明被证实了
No, but since George's alibi checked out,
我们就得查看所有的可能性
we're gonna have to look at all of our options,
包括这种不太可能的
including the unlikely ones.
根据乔治的地图
According to George's map,
这个遗弃的设施通道
This abandoned utility access
就在詹森的大楼下面
runs directly under Jansen's facility.
是的  不过有谁如此恨汤姆
Yeah, but who would hate Tom enough
以至于愿意穿过五英尺的混凝土地道去杀他
to tunnel through 5 feet of concrete to kill him?
不知道  不过...
I don't know, but...
不过有人似乎真的这么做了
but it looks like someone did.
卡塞尔  抬我上去
Castle, boost me up.
为什么每次都是我在下面
Why am I always on the bottom?
遵命  亲爱的
Yes, dear.
星球上潮湿的入口
Planets dank access ways...
难道没有让你想起《异形》吗
is it just me, or does this remind you of "Alien"?
我知道你希望这就像科幻片那样
I know that you want this to be science-fiction,
但我们不是在太空里
but we are not in space.
确实  但难道你都不希望如此吗
No, but wouldn't you like it to be?
拜托  你是科幻极客
Come on, you're a sci-fi geek.
-你难道不想去火星吗  -我当然想
- Wouldn't you just love to go to Mars? - Of course I would.
所以我才申请了
That's why I applied
去年伊恩·拉什尔的项目
to Ian Rasher's program last year!
等等  什么  你申请了登陆火星计划
Wait, what? You applied to go to Mars?
还不带我  什么时候啊
Without me? When?
我们当时吵架了
Well, we were fighting.
好吧  我活该
Oh, okay. Well, I deserved that.
天哪  卡塞尔
Oh, geez, Castle.
看到什么了吗
See anything?
确实有人来过
Someone did tunnel up.
卡塞尔
Castle?
我想我找到了凶器
I think I found the murder weapon.
你听到了吗
Did you hear that?
听到什么
Whoa. Hear what?
怎么回事
What happened?
那里有东西
Something's down here.
不是人吗
Some thing?
那到底是什么啊
What the hell is that?
我跟你说了太像《异形》了
Told you this felt like "Alien."
卡塞尔  够了  这不是《异形》
Castle, stop. This is not "Alien."
你觉得那像人类吗
Did that look human to you?
确实不像
Actually, no.
那就对了
Right.
我打赌那是异形
See, I'm betting it's a xenomorph
被困地球  被模拟室
stranded here on earth, attracted to the simulation
吸引  因为它需要毒气环境
because it needs the toxic environment.
也许它是觉得汤姆侵犯了自己的领地
It probably saw Tom as encroaching on its territory
才杀掉了他
and killed him for it.
你干什么
What are you doing?
检查你身上有没有抓伤咬伤
I'm checking you for bites and scratches.
确保你没被产卵
Making sure you didn't somehow get impregnated.
你要觉得我这样受孕  那我们真得谈谈
If you think that's how I get pregnant, we need to talk.
在那
There!
贝克特
Beckett!
它蜕皮了
It shed its skin.
不是皮
It's not skin.
是防毒面具
It's a gas mask.
这是个呼吸管  人类用的
It's a breathing hose. For a human.
因为模拟室的烟雾
To protect themselves from the fumes of the simulation.
确实有人想闯进来
Someone was trying to break in.
没错  这里是进入点
Yes, this was the access point.
为什么会有人想溜进我的模拟室
Why would someone tunnel into my simulation?
也许是你的对手
Well, maybe it's one of your competitors.
目的可能是刺探情报或者搞破坏
It could be espionage... or sabotage.
也许被害人发现了他们
And our victim might have found out
并威胁说要揭发
and threatened to expose them.
不管是哪种  这能解释
Either way, this explains what he saw,
他为什么觉得当时还有别人在
why he thought there was someone else in there with him.
他们是怎么躲开我的监控摄像头的
How did they elude my cameras?
也许他们和你项目中的
Well, maybe they were working with someone
内部人员串通
that was involved in your program
知道摄像头关闭的时间
and knew when the cameras would be blacked out.
失陪
Excuse me.
鉴证科证实了
So, CSU just confirmed it.
螺丝刀上的血迹确实是汤姆的
The blood on the screwdriver belonged to Tom.
-确实是本案的凶器  -上面有指纹吗
- It's our murder weapon. - Okay, any prints?
没有  但如果凶手当时在模拟室里
No, but if the killer was in the simulation...
那肯定是戴着手套的
then they would have been wearing gloves.
好吧  那防毒面具呢
Um, okay, what about the gas mask?
有什么线索吗
Anything from that?
看起来像军用设备
It looks military,
但我们还在试图追踪来源
But we're still trying to run it down.
还有  莱恩正在查看周边
Meantime, Ryan's pulling camera footage
区域的监控录像
from the surrounding area.
幸运的话
Maybe we'll get lucky,
也许我们可以
catch our alien exiting
看到外星凶手走出通道出口
one of the access points to the utility tunnel.
结果可能要等明早出来了
Probably won't know anything till morning.
好的  保持联络
All right, keep me apprised.
你帮我们想想有谁
Okay, why don't you think about anyone
会想要破坏你的模拟室
that would have wanted to breach your simulation,
我们查到什么会通知你
and we'll keep you posted on what we find.
好
Yeah.
天哪
Oh, my god.
诡异的一天
What a day.
我觉得现在身上还有蜘蛛网呢
I feel like I'm still covered in spider webs.
简直等不及冲个热水澡了
I cannot wait to take a hot shower.
也许我可以  和你一起洗
Oh, maybe I could, uh, join you.
那真好
Ooh, that'd be nice.
我们可以放松一下  倒杯红酒
We could relax, have a glass of wine --
听到了吗
Do you hear that?
是你妈妈的声音
It's your mom.
还有本
And Ben.
而且阿莱克西斯也在
And Alexis is here.
还带着朋友
With friends.
不如我们去旅馆吧
Maybe we could go to a hotel.
你还说你可以忍受
And yet you think you could survive
在一个小太空舱里
being stuck in a space capsule
和四个人一起困一年呢
with four other people for a year.
我可以啊  如果你是四人之一的话
I could, if you were one of those people.
你们俩啊
You guys.
单独找个房间吧
Get a room.
我们很愿意啊  如果还有空房间的话
We would, if there were any left!
也许你不该这么快就把你的房子转租了
Maybe you shouldn't have been so quick to sublet your place.
我们可以定个时间表
You know, maybe we can just set up a schedule,
或者让他们提前通知我们一声
or they could give us a heads-up
不必让我们回家时大吃一惊
and let us know what to expect when we get home.
我要开一个家庭会议
I'm gonna call a family meeting.
或者我们直接去火星吧
Or we could just go to Mars.
我想你不会喜欢住火星的
Yeah, I don't think you'd be happy there.
那里没有淋浴  有速溶咖啡
There's no showers, there's instant coffee,
而且你得自己动手
and you have to bag your own --
早啊  卡塞尔夫妇
Hey, Castles!
监控录像查到什么线索了吗
Hey. Any luck on that security-cam footage?
没有  这个外星人走的肯定是
Nada. Your alien must've accessed
没有摄像头的地下通道
the underground where there wasn't any coverage.
但防毒面具的调查倒是有进展
But we did have better luck with that gas mask.
鉴证科在面具内侧发现了
CSU was able to pull exhaled-breath condensate
呼出凝结物
from inside the face plate.
里面包含着少量DNA
It contained trace amounts of DNA.
系统里找到匹配了吗
We get a match in the system?
我们系统里没有
Not our system,
但2018火星计划中
but as part of the Mars 2018 program,
每位申请者都要提交DNA样本
every applicant had to submit sample DNA.
所以我们在那个系统里进行检索
So, we ran it against that database,
-猜猜找到了谁  -不会吧
- and guess who popped up. - No!
外星人是格兰杰啊
Granger's our alien?
他是进出了模拟室
So, he was getting in and out,
只是走的路出乎意料
just not the way we thought.
也就是说他的不在场证明是谎话
Which means his alibi was a lie.
当他得知我们查到他了
As soon as he knew we were onto him --
他就回去销毁证据
he went back to destroy the evidence.
你把他带过来了吗
You bringing him in?
找到的话我会的
I would if we could find him,
但他不在家
But he's not at his place
也不接电话
and he's not answering his phone.
发个全境通告
Okay, put out an APB.
地下黑暗中遭遇后  他可能已经逃跑了
After our encounter in the dark, he might be on the run.
我也许有办法找到他
I may know how to find him.
那个防毒面具  并不是常见的东西
That gas mask -- it's an uncommon make.
城里能提供它的卖家不多
Not a lot of suppliers in the city carry them.
但我通过它的序列号
But I was able to track down the serial number
找到了上城一家军用设备供应商
to an army/navy supply store uptown.
他们证明面具是格兰杰买的了吗
Did they confirm that Granger bought it?
没有  面具是几个月前卖出的了
No, the mask was purchased a couple months back,
所以没人记得买主
so no one remembered the buyer,
但付款的是个公司帐户
but it was charged to a corporate account --
一个叫纽顿实业的公司
a company called Newton Endeavors.
-都了解多少情况  -不多
- What do we know about them? - Not much.
网上找不到任何信息
I couldn't find anything on the web,
但我找到了一个地址
but I was able to track down an address
在皇后区的威利点
out in Queens in Willets Point.
干的好
Well done.
纽顿实业
Newton Endeavors.
听着就和太空有关
Sounds space related.
太空  最后的边疆[《星际迷航》台词]
Space -- the final frontier.
开启卡塞尔和贝克特的冒险之旅
These are the voyages of Castle and Beckett.
不间断的任务
Their ongoing mission --
探索不同的犯案动机
to explore strange new motives,
找出罪案的新证人和新疑犯
to seek out new witnesses and new suspects for murder,
勇于探索...
to boldly go where --
就是这儿
Oh, right over here.
打扰
Excuse me.
这是纽顿实业吗
Is this Newton Endeavors?
抱歉  这是私人领地
Oh, I'm sorry. This is private property.
请你们离开
I'm gonna have to ask you to leave.
纽约警察
NYPD.
请你开门
I'm gonna have to ask you to open that door.
不是吧
What the hell?
这是我的幻觉  还是这太空舱看着很眼熟
Is it just me, or does that capsule look incredibly familiar?
谁会想仿造詹森的火星移居地啊
Who would want to build a replica of Jansen's Mars colony?
他的竞争对手
The competition.
格兰杰一定是潜入模拟室
Granger must have been breaking into the sim
帮詹森的对手窃取技术
to steal technology for Jansen's competitors.
我不介意付他们三倍工资
I don't care if we have to pay them triple.
我们不能再落后于人了
We cannot fall any further behind.
我想我知道是谁了
And I think I know which one.
伊恩·拉什尔爵士
Yep. Sir Ian Rasher.
亿万富翁  纨绔子弟  冒险家
Billionaire playboy adventurer.
也可能是谋杀案从犯
And possible accessory to murder.
也许你该反思
You may want to rethink
申请加入他项目的做法
your application to his program.
拉什尔先生吗  纽约警察  贝克特探长
Mr. Rasher? Detective Beckett, NYPD.
-能聊一聊吗  -当然
- I was wondering if we could have a word. - Of course.
我有什么可以帮到纽约警察的
What can I do for New York's finest?
你可以先告诉我克林特·格兰杰在哪里
Well, you can start by telling me where Clint Granger is.
抱歉  探长
I'm sorry, detective.
我恐怕不认识这个人
I'm afraid I don't know who that is.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
看看周围  我猜他就是你雇来
Because looking around, i'm guessing he's the guy that you hired
窃取韦格·詹森火星模拟室的人
to steal Viggo Jansen's plans for the mars simulation.
探长
Detective,
我雇的是世上最好的工程师
I employ the world's best engineers.
我为什么要浪费时间得到我对手的技术
Why would I bother wasting my time on my competitor's technology?
也许因为你在逐渐落后于他
Maybe because you're falling behind them.
众所周知你上两次火箭发射
It's no secret your last two rocket launches
都以悲惨失败告终
were spectacular failures.
你想要获胜
You want to win,
所以你需要在竞争中占上风
so you needed to buy a competitive advantage.
当詹森的一名队员
And after one of Jansen's team members
发现你的目的时
discovered what you were up to --
对于你这样声望和爵位的人
A man with your reputation and knighthood --
你没得选择  只能杀了他
you had no choice but to have him killed.
杀
Killed?
谁被杀了
Who was killed?
詹森手下的一个宇航员汤姆·里奇伍德
One of Jansen's astronauts -- Tom Richwood.
我和这件事没有关联
I had nothing to do with that.
要让我相信你
Well, the best way to convince me of that
就告诉我格兰杰在哪里
is to tell me where Granger is.
除非你更想入狱
unless you prefer prison.
对  我是伊恩爵士派的间谍
Okay, yeah... I was spying for Sir Ian.
他承诺事成之后让我当他团队的驾驶员
He promised me the pilot slot on his mission if I did.
但关于汤姆的事我没有撒谎
But I was telling the truth about Tom.
他不是我杀的
I didn't kill him.
我有不在场证明  不是吗
I have an alibi, remember?
不在场证明是可以伪造的
Alibis can be bought.
我们在防毒面具上发现了你的DNA
We found your DNA on the gas mask.
我们知道通道里的是你
We know it was you in the access way.
因为我不想事情看起来
Because I didn't want it to look like
和我有牵连
I had anything to do with this.
我去是为了确保我没有留下任何物证
I went to make sure that I hadn't left anything there
能让你们追查到我
that could point back to me.
比如凶器吗
Like the murder weapon?
你们真觉得如果是我杀了汤姆
Oh, come on. If I killed Tom, do you really think
我会傻到把凶器留在那儿吗
I'd be stupid enough to leave the murder weapon there?
再说  我根本没进过模拟室
Besides, I was never inside the simulation.
那太冒险了
That would've been way too risky.
太容易被发现
Too many opportunities to get caught.
那为什么要用防毒面具
Then why the gas mask?
那只是个预防措施
It was a precaution.
我并不是要用那个通道进去
I wasn't using the tunnel to get in.
那是个交接点
It was a drop point.
有人和你里应外合
You were working with someone on the inside.
我需要资源  而他需要钱
I needed access. He needed money.
所以我们达成了交易
So we struck a deal.
他帮我下载方案图纸和规划
He'd download schematics and plans
然后放在通道里
and drop them for me in the tunnel.
是谁
Who?
-米哈伊尔·丹科夫  -那个宇航员
- Mikhail Dankov. - The astronaut?
如果汤姆发现了他  那或许他就是凶手
If Tom was onto him, then maybe he's your killer.
我们查过他的追踪器
We checked his tracker.
凶案发生时他在栖息地
He was inside the habitat at the time of the murder.
米哈伊尔知道如果他的行踪被记录的话
Mikhail knew if his movements were being recorded,
他就无法为我们的所作所为逃避惩罚
he'd never get away with what we were doing.
所以他打败了系统
So he beat the system.
他在植入追踪器之前就克隆了数据
He cloned his tracker before they embedded it under his skin.
只要没人发现  他可以在任何时间溜出去
As long as no one was looking, he could slip out at any time.
米哈伊尔
Mikhail?
什么事
Yes?
我想和你谈谈
I'd like a few words with you.
谈什么
What about?
你和克林特·格兰杰的合作关系
Your business relationship with Clint Granger.
别这样米哈伊尔  你疯了
Come on, Mikhail. You're crazy!
哥们儿  你能跑哪去  你在火星呢
Bro, where you gonna run? You're on mars!
虽然我不想承认  但是出来的感觉真好
I hate to admit, but it's good to be out.
继续
Go ahead.
大家怎么说来着  新鲜空气  时代广场
What do they say? Fresh air, times square?
经历过火星模拟室  监狱应该是小菜一碟了吧
Well, after the mars simulation, prison should be a breeze.
我是在贩卖信息  多大的事儿啊
So I was trading information. Big deal.
我去火星之后就再也不回来了
I was leaving the planet and never coming back.
我要确保我的家人受到好的照料
I wanted to make sure my family was taken care of.
真高尚
Oh, noble.
你们老美啊  一点点金钱交易无伤大雅
You Americans. A little corruption never hurt anyone.
我不认为汤姆会赞同
I don't think Tom would agree.
汤姆  汤姆是个浑蛋
Tom? Tom was jackass.
所有人都受不了他克扣粮食供给
Drove everyone crazy the way he doled out food and supplies
还用每个人细小的错误来建立影响力
and tried to leverage everyone for making even tiniest error.
相信我  大家可能不敢说出来
Trust me, they may be scared to say it,
但没人为他的死感到伤心
but no one's sad he's dead.
没有人期待在另一个星球
No one was looking forward to spending rest of lives
和他共度余生
with him on other planet.
但你是唯一一个在他被谋杀时下落不明的
And yet, you are the only one that is unaccounted for
也就是说
during his murder,
你是唯一一个能杀死他的人
which means you are the only one that could've killed him.
不  我不是
Mm, no. I could not.
我能证明案发时我在哪儿
I can prove where I was during the murder.
怎么证明
How?
金指挥官让我去工程区时
When commander Kim sent me down to engineering,
我用仅有的时间拍照片
I used rare time alone to take pictures
在生命补给处帮格兰杰下载图纸
and download schematics from life support to give to Granger.
存有所有照片的内存盘还在我这里
I still have the drive with all of my photos.
照片上标有时间
They're time-stamped with the mission clock.
你的不在场证明是当时你在为格兰杰窃取信息
So, your alibi is that you were spying for Granger?
去看我的照片你们就知道了
Go. Look at my photos. You'll see.
我翻阅了米哈伊尔的所有照片
So, I went through all of Mikhail's photos
从汤姆被杀的那个晚上开始
from the night Tom was murdered.
他没有说谎
As you can see, he's telling the truth.
看到他的镜像了吗
See his reflection?
是的
Yeah.
时间模块确认了时间
And the module clock confirms the time.
他可能仿制了时间
Maybe he faked the time,
要不整件事都是格兰杰做的
or maybe it was Granger after all.
不是格兰杰  莱恩  前一张
It wasn't Granger. Uh, Ryan, go back.
就是这张
To -- there, now...
放大窗户
Zoom in on the window.
看右下方
Look down on the bottom right.
那是探测车吗
Is that the rover?
我以为计算机记载
I thought the computer said
谋杀时它处于停靠状态
that it was docked during the murder.
很显然  计算机弄错了
Clearly, the computer was wrong.
放大探测车的机械臂
Now, uh, push in on the Rover's arm.
滤掉其他反射图像
Filter out some of that reflection.
是那把螺丝刀
It's the screwdriver.
那就是拿着凶器的凶手
There's your killer holding the murder weapon.
是探测车干的
The Rover did it.
探测车开出去了  不对啊
The rover was out? This can't be right.
米拉的所有数据都显示
All the data from M.I.R.A. indicates
汤姆被杀时  探测车处于停靠状态
that the rover was docked when Tom was killed.
数据弄错了
I'd say the data's wrong.
根据你的文献
And according to your literature,
那辆探测车有着能够
that rover has the speed and dexterity
精准杀人的速度和灵巧度
to kill with mathematical precision.
詹森先生  都有谁能够操控探测车
Mr. Jansen, who has access to the rover controls?
宇航员吗  或是控制中心的人
One of your astronauts? Someone at mission control?
没人能操控
No one has access.
探测车是很复杂的机械设备
The rover is an extremely complex piece of equipment.
人工操作  太容易出错
Under human control, there's too high a margin for error,
所以我们将其设计为只能通过计算机控制
So we designed it to interface solely with the computer.
我们的宇航员描述其想要完成的任务
Our astronauts describe the sort of task they want carried out,
米拉负责执行
and M.I.R.A. executes it.
有没有可能某人要求她杀死汤姆
Is it possible someone could have asked her to kill Tom?
米拉不会执行那种命令的
M.I.R.A. wouldn't comply with that sort of command.
但这不太对劲
But something's wrong.
我需要跟她谈谈
I need to talk to her.
能不能找个私密的地方谈
Well, is there somewhere we can do that privately
不被他人偷听的地方
without anyone hearing?
有  模拟室中的计算机模块舱
Yeah, the computer-module pod inside the sim.
怎么了
What's going on?
很快就会让你知道
I'll let you know soon.
这里
In here.
好了
There.
我切断了与栖息地其他人的通讯
I've cut off communications with the rest of the habitat.
没人能听见我们
No one can hear us.
是你吗  詹森博士
Is that you, Dr. Jansen?
是的  米拉
Yes, M.I.R.A.
你来火星干什么  博士
What are you doing on Mars, doctor?
我来跟你谈谈
I came to talk to you.
你还记得贝克特探长和理查德·卡塞尔吧
You remember Detective Beckett and Richard Castle.
当然  有什么需要帮忙的
Of course. How can I help you?
我们是要审问计算机吗
Are we seriously about to interrogate a computer?
探长  "审问"一词暗示
Detective, the word "Interrogate"
你认为我做错了什么事
implies you believe I am guilty of something.
你认为我做错了什么
Of what do you think I am guilty?
至少她没有请律师
Well, at least she's not asking for a lawyer.
米拉
M.I.R.A.,
我们想知道  汤姆·里奇伍德被杀时
we'd like to know where the rover was
探测车在哪里
when Tom Richwood was killed.
我已经把这个讯息给你了  探长
I already gave you that information, Detective.
探测车处于停靠状态
The rover was docked.
米拉  我们知道探测车并未停靠
M.I.R.A., we know the rover wasn't docked.
你们怎么知道的
How do you know?
我们有照片  证据
We have photographs, evidence.
你们的证据有误
Your evidence is incorrect.
探测车处于停靠状态
The rover was docked.
米拉  在汤姆死前
M.I.R.A., prior to Tom's death,
有人指示你启动探测车吗
did someone instruct you to activate the rover?
她在使用更多的电力  不对劲
She's drawing more power. Something's wrong.
不  探测车并未启动
No. The rover wasn't activated.
探测车处于停靠状态
The rover was docked.
有可能是他人篡改了她的存储吗
Is it possible someone could have altered her memory?
没人篡改我的存储  卡塞尔先生
No one altered my memory, Mr. Castle.
我的存储很好
My memory is perfect.
她存储核心被设计成封闭系统
Her memory core was designed to be a closed system.
无法被篡改  但出了什么问题
It can't be altered, but something's off.
米拉  在所有系统运行一级诊断程序
M.I.R.A., run a level-one diagnostic on all systems.
没必要运行诊断程序
There is no need to run a diagnostic.
所有系统都处于最佳状态
All systems are optimal.
那也运行一遍  好吗
How about we run it anyway?
抱歉  我做不到
I'm sorry. I can't do that.
为什么
Why not?
那样做违背我的运行参数
It violates my operational parameters.
只是简单的诊断程序  违背了什么参数
It's a simple diagnostic. What parameter does it violate?
那会危害整个任务
It will compromise the mission.
诊断程序怎么会危害整个任务
How will a diagnostic compromise the mission?!
回答这个问题会危害整个任务
Answering that question will compromise the mission.
-我不明白  -我明白
- I don't understand. - I think I do.
她知道她在说谎
She knows she's lying to us,
如果她运行诊断程序
and if she runs those diagnostics,
我们就会发现真相
we'll discover the truth.
真相会危害到整个任务
And that truth will somehow put the mission at risk.
她是台机器  她不会说谎
She's a machine. She can't lie.
你说过她被编程拥有学习能力
You said that she's programmed to learn.
如果有人教她说谎呢
What if somebody taught her how?
如果有人利用她来杀人
What if someone used her to kill
然后利用她掩盖罪行
and then to help cover up the crime?
不  她的核心参数是无法被修改的
No, her core parameters can't be altered.
她被编程保护整个任务以及参与任务的每个人
She's programmed to protect the mission and everyone on it.
但如果那些运行参数
But what if those operational parameters are
彼此矛盾呢
in conflict with each other?
如果她需要保护的人
What if someone she's programmed to protect
对整个任务是个威胁呢
is a threat to the mission?
米拉  你对汤姆·里奇伍德如何看待
Um, M.I.R.A., how would you classify Tom Richwood?
汤姆·里奇伍德军士长
Sergeant Major Tom Richwood,
驾驶员  系统工程专家
pilot, systems engineering specialist.
-好  好  -已死亡
- Right. Right, okay. Um... - Deceased.
汤姆对整个任务是个威胁吗
Was Tom a threat to the mission?
是的
Yes.
为什么
Why?
是谁告诉你汤姆是个威胁的
Who told you Tom was a threat?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我未经授权给予你此讯息
I'm not authorized to give you that information.
因为在她的系统中
Because in her mind,
那个讯息会危害整个任务
that information would be a threat to the mission.
肯定还有其他办法找出真相
There's got to be another way to find out.
有
There is.
我可以重启她
I can reboot her.
她所有学到的东西都会被消除
Everything she's learned will be wiped,
但储存的内容都会得以保存
but all recorded memory will stay intact.
我们很快就会知道到底发生了什么
We can find out pretty quickly what happened.
那是什么
What's that?
有人打开了与外界连接的通气口
Someone's opened the vents to the outside!
我们暴露在外界空气中了
We're taking in atmosphere!
是米拉  她在试图保护自己
It's M.I.R.A. She's trying to protect herself.
不  米拉  回答我
No! M.I.R.A., don't shut me out!
你说这有害  但不会杀死我们
You said that this was harmful but it wouldn't kill us, right?
短期不会  长期暴露其中是致命的
Short term -- long term, it's deadly!
我们得出去
We have to get out of here!
锁住了
It's locked!
求助
Call for help!
通讯切断了
Communications are dead!
米拉  开门
M.I.R.A., open the door!
打开舱门
Open the pod bay door!
我想去火星
I wanted to go to mars...
不是死在火星上
not die on mars.
等下  我们不是在火星上
Wait a minute. We're not on mars.
我们在地球上
We're on earth.
喂
Hello?
贝克特
Beckett?
你是说电脑试图杀死你们吗
Are you saying that the computer tried to kill you?
就像《2001太空漫游》
Yeah, just like in "2001."
库布里克没弄错
Kubrick was right.
人工智能不是个好主意
A.I. is a bad idea.
米拉不是人工智能
M.I.R.A.'s not A.I.
是的  她能学习  适应  但她是机器
Yes, she can learn and adapt, but she's a machine.
她无法自我思考
She cannot think for herself.
那她为什么要杀死我们
Then why'd she try to kill us?
那不是米拉
It wasn't M.I.R.A.
我们刚刚断开了服务器
We just pulled apart the server.
有人在重启系统中附加了一个子程序
Someone embedded a subroutine into the O.S. reset program.
一旦你们试图重启她
The moment that you tried to reboot her,
子程序启动  将你们困在里面
that subroutine activated, trapping you guys inside.
它同时触发了米拉存储电路的倾卸
It also triggered a dump of M.I.R.A.'s memory circuits.
所有的任务数据都没了
All the mission data is gone.
那么这是幕后黑手
So this was a failsafe
安装的故障保护
installed by whoever was behind this.
我们本不该发现探测车或是米拉的异样
We were never meant to find out about the rover or M.I.R.A.,
万一我们发现了
and on the off chance that we did,
凶手希望我们不会更近一步
the killer wanted to make sure we didn't get any further.
通过杀死唯一的证人
By killing the only witness --
米拉和她的存储体
M.I.R.A. and her memory banks.
肯定是某个宇航员干的
It has to be one of the astronauts.
他们是唯一能安放子程序的人
They're the only ones who could've planted that subroutine,
也是唯一能说服米拉
the only ones who could've convince M.I.R.A.
汤姆是个威胁的人
that Tom was a threat.
但是存储内容无法恢复
Yeah, but with the memory data unrecoverable,
我们没法知道到底是谁
it's impossible to know which one.
不  有办法
No. Not impossible.
事实上
As a matter of fact,
只有一个解释说得通
there's only one explanation that makes sense.
你在开玩笑吧
You can't be serious.
你认为我们中的某人是凶手
You think one of us is the killer?
这几乎是完美犯罪
And it was almost the perfect crime.
凶手只需要一个替罪羊
All the mastermind needed was someone to pin it on,
米哈伊尔刚好派上用场
and that's where Mikhail came in.
凶手一定是发现
The killer must've found out
米哈伊尔在倒卖商业机密
that Mikhail was selling secrets,
使他成为最完美的替罪羊
which made him the perfect patsy.
凶手只需确保
All they had to do was make sure
米哈伊尔在汤姆被杀时没有不在场证明就行
that Mikhail was unaccounted for during Tom's murder.
再就是把凶器安放在他的交接点
That and plant the weapon at his drop-off point.
一石两鸟
Killing two birds with one stone --
人见人恨的汤姆
Tom, whom everybody hated,
和倒卖机密的米哈伊尔
and Mikhail, who was selling secrets.
于是凶手派米哈伊尔去工程区
So they sent Mikhail to engineering,
他不会知道所发生的一切
where he would be blind to everything that happened.
可惜他没有待在那
Only he didn't stay there.
他去了生命补给室
Instead, he went to life support,
通过一张照片  就揭露了一切
Where, with one photo, he expos everything.
金指挥官  是你在维修时
Commander Kim, it was you who sent Mikhail to engineering
派米哈伊尔去工程区的
during the repair, wasn't it?
-是的  但这没什么奇怪的  -的确
- Yes, though there's nothing unusual about that. - No.
但根据流程
But according to procedure,
安琪拉不是应该去辅助他吗
Isn't Angela supposed to be there backing him up?
是的  但我需要她在这里做检查
Yes, but I needed her up here checking protocols.
那可不能证明我是凶手
That hardly makes me a murderer.
再说我都没有离开模块舱
And I never even left the module
所以我无法在通道中安放杀人凶器
so I...I couldn't have planted the murder weapon in the tunnel.
的确
No.
但是哈伦博士和安琪拉可以做到
But Dr. Haroun and Angela could have done that.
你俩在外面停留了10分钟
The two of you were outside together for 10 minutes.
是去查看汤姆并恢复供电
Yes, checking on Tom and restoring power.
那时所有摄像机都停用了
While all the cameras were down,
给了你足够的时间丢弃凶器
Giving you enough time to ditch the murder weapon
并清理探测车上的证据
and clean any forensic evidence off the rover.
太扯了
That's ridiculous.
你这是要一一列举我们的嫌疑吗
Are you just gonna go after us one by one?
那时我一直跟拉什曼在一起
I was with Rusham the whole time.
他没有接近过探测车
He didn't go anywhere near the rover.
安琪拉也没有
And neither did Angela.
所以才说犯案者很聪明
And that's what makes this crime so clever.
从一开始
From the beginning,
你们三个就一直在给彼此提供不在场证明
the three of you have been able to alibi each other out
因为你们都参与其中
because you were all in on it together.
只有你们三个合谋
It would've taken the three of you colluding
才能说服米拉汤姆会危害整个任务
to convince M.I.R.A. that Tom was threatening the mission.
考虑到你们对汤姆的看法
And given the way that you felt about Tom,
你们知道汤姆在团队中  一切都会搞砸
you knew that the team couldn't survive with him on it.
他的确是个威胁  尤其是在环境恶劣的星球上
He was a threat, especially on a hostile planet.
于是  在被关在这狭小空间
So, after six months of being locked up
六个月后  你们决定
in this tin can together, you decided
比起牺牲成为第一批
that rather than sacrifice your chance
踏上火星的人类的机会
at being the first human beings to stand on mars,
还是用一条人命换来永垂不朽更划算
you would put your shot at immortality ahead of another man's life.
这是个有趣的推理
That's a...fascinating theory,
但米拉的存储都没了  你没有证据
But with M.I.R.A.'s memory gone, you have no proof.
我们也是这么想的
You know, that's what we thought, as well.
知道詹森博士告知我们米拉的黑盒子
Until Dr. Jansen told us about M.I.R.A's black box.
由于出现灾难性故障
In the event of a catastrophic failure,
她把她的数据传到了最近的卫星上
she pulses all her data to the nearest satellite.
你们与她所有的交谈
All your conversations with her,
全部的内容
everything you three did,
都在上面
It's all there.
坏消息是  你们谁都去不了火星了
So, the bad news is, none of you are going to mars.
好消息是
Good news is,
第一个老实交代的人
the first one to cooperate
判刑的时间最短
will get the least amount of jail time.
没想到他们这么快就招供了
I just didn't expect them to cave that quickly.
真是个好策略  卡塞尔
That was a clever ruse, Castle.
这招好用真开心
I'm just glad it worked.
如果没成功
And if there's not
真该有个灾难性故障黑匣子卫星
a catastrophic-black-box satellite, there should be.
你认为詹森会怎么做
What do you think is gonna happen with Jansen?
他是业界先锋  梦想家
Uh, he's a pioneer. He's a visionary.
或许2018年他做不到
He may not get there in 2018,
但我打赌他肯定还是第一个
but I'm willing to bet that he's gonna be the first.
这案子后  你还想去火星吗
So, after all of this, you still want to go to Mars?
当然
Oh, of course.
但我认为我会等到他们有头等舱服务
But I think I'm gonna wait till they have
到时咱俩一起去
first-class service so we can go together.
你认为
Do you think at any point,
那时候有没有那个宇航员对另一个人说
one of those astronauts turned to the others and said,
"杀掉汤姆可能是个坏主意"
"Maybe killing Tom is a really bad idea"?
我认为当人们被关在密闭空间内
I think that when people are stuck together in a small space
很长时间后  他们就看不清问题了
for a long period of time, they lose perspective.
说到这个
Speaking of which,
不是要召开家庭会议吗
Um, wasn't there supposed to be a family meeting tonight?
是的
There is.
我告诉阿丽克西斯不用来
I told Alexis she did not need to come
因为我想跟你俩单独谈
because I wanted to talk to the two of you alone.
我知道
Now, I know that things
最近这里比较混乱
have been a little frenetic around here,
阿丽克西斯和她的朋友
what with alexis and her friends
你俩非常规的作息时间
and the two of you in anout at all sorts of odd hours and --
别忘了你和你的新男友大晚上唱歌
And you and your new boyfriend doing late-night medleys.
是的
I -- well, yeah, that.
所以我决定
So, I have decided --
我不想让你俩难过
And I don't want to upset either one of you --
我决定找一个自己的地方
that I am going to look for a place of my own.
居住吗
To live?
是的
Well, yes.
当然  不是马上搬走
I mean, not right away, of course.
想找个完美的住处
I mean, it's gonna take me a while
得花点时间
to find exactly the right space.
母亲  我只是召开家庭会议
Mother, I was just calling a family meeting.
没想让你搬走
I didn't intend for you to move out.
亲爱的  这跟你无关  只跟我有关
Darling, this is not about you. Thiss about me.
把这当做是进化吧
Think of it as a kind of evolution, you know?
我现在事业干得不错
I'm -- I'm starting to do very well for myself,
我想过不了多久
and I am guessing that, uh, before too long,
就该有小卡塞尔
there's gonna be a few more little Castles,
在这里搞破坏了
creating havoc around here, and --
我认为你俩
And I think the two of you
应该独享这里
deserve to have this place to yourselves.
如果有需要帮忙的事  告诉我
Let me know if there's anything I can do.
我会的
OH...I will.
好了  我该走了
Okay. I am off.
今晚我跟本杰明一起过
I'm spending the evening with Benjamin.
别等我哦  拜
So, don't wait up! Bye!
我完全没想到
I did not expect that.
出人意料是她的专长
The unexpected is her specialty.
好安静
It's so quiet.
非常安静
It's really, really quiet.
或许我们应该出去吃
Maybe we should go out.
街角刚好开了家印度菜馆
There's a great indian restaurant that just opened up around the corner.
气氛超赞
Fantastic atmosphere.
吵得很
It's loud.
分贝很高  人也很多
Super-loud. Lot of people
全是人
Lots and lots of people.